Register of the Gerald Lee Warren papers, 1956-1994
Hoover Institution Archives
- General Subject File, 1969-1976 (Boxes 225-228)
  - Speeches and writings by others
    - Methvin, Eugene H., "Chief Justice Burger Balances the Scale," Reader's Digest, 1975 April (Box-folder 228: 20)
    - Metz, Robert, "The Biggest Man in Broadcasting," New York Magazine, 1975 July 7 (Box-folder 228: 21)
    - Newman, Edwin, "Comment," speech, NBC News, New York, 1971 April 11 (Box-folder 228: 22)
    - O'Neil, Paul, "The Prime Time of Walter Cronkite,", undated (Box-folder 228: 23)
    - Reagan, Ronald, remarks, Eisenhower tribute dinner, Washington Hilton Hotel, 1969 October 14 (Box-folder 228: 24)
    - Reagan, Ronald, "The Ronald Reagan Column,", 1975 May-July (Box-folder 228: 25-31)
    - Reinert, Al, "Bob and George Go to Washington or the Post-Watergate Scandal," Texas Monthly, 1974 April (Box-folder 228: 32)
    - Saud, Al-Faisal, Prince of Saudi Arabia, remarks on "Saudi Arabia and the United States," Houston, Texas, 1976 September 23 (Box-folder 228: 33)
    - Sherrod, Drury R., "Selective Perception of Political Candidates,", undated (Box-folder 228: 34)
    - Sidey, Hugh, "You Can Walk to Work, and the Pay Isn't Bad," Today's Health, 1974 November (Box-folder 228: 35)
    - Simon, William E., "Big Government and our Economic Woes," Reader's Digest, 1975 April (Box-folder 228: 36)
    - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksander, "Solzhenitsyn Speaks Out," Russian Thought, translated into English by Albert and Tanya Schmidt, National Review, 1975 January 16, June 6 (Box-folder 228: 37)
    - Stanton, Frank, "If We Bury the First Amendment Will We Rest in Peace?," keynote address, Sigma Delta Chi national convention, Atlanta, 1968 November 21 (Box-folder 228: 38)
    - Stockman, David, "The Social Pork Barrel," The Public Interest, 1975 May 18 (Box-folder 228: 39)
    - Terrill, Ross, "The 800,000,000, China and the World,", undated (Box-folder 228: 40)
    - Terrill, Ross, "The 800,000,000, Report from China,", undated (Box-folder 228: 41)
    - Thimmesch, Nick, "The Ron Ziegler behind Ron Ziegler," The Washington Post-Potomac, 1974 February 24 (Box-folder 228: 42)
    - Waldo, Dwight, "Reflections on Public Morality,", 1974 May (Box-folder 228: 43)
      Presentation in a series of lectures sponsored by the Maxwell School of Citizenship and Public Affairs in conjunction with the annual meetings of the American Society for Public Administration, Syracuse. Reprinted with the permission of the publisher from Administration and Society, November, 1974.
    - Witcover, Jules, "Salvaging the Presidential Press Conference," Columbia Journalism Review, 1970 Fall (Box-folder 228: 44)
    - Witt, John W., "The Confidentiality of Records and Their Effects on Public Managers: Are Police Intelligence Files Really Confidential?," speech delivered to the San Diego County chapter, American Society for Public Administration, Caesar's Restaurant, Mission Valley, 1976 August 18 (Box-folder 228: 45)
- Oversize Materials, 1966-1975 (Box 229)
  - Appointment diary of Richard M. Nixon, 1973-1975 (Box 229)
  - Certificates, 1966-1975
  - Reprints of Soviet supersonic passenger airliner (Aeroflot), 1972-1973
  - Writing by others
    - Hersey, John, "The President," The New York Times Magazine, 1975 April 20
- Sound Recordings, 1923-1974 (Record cabinet, Cassette cabinet)
  - Sound discs (12" vinyl), Russian souvenirs, 1923-1973 (Record cabinet)
    - M. Glinka romances
    - Men of big flight
    - My boundless motherland (2 discs)
  - Sound cassettes, 1973-1974 (Cassette cabinet)
    - "Beating of the retreat," Amman, Jordan, 1974 June 18
    - Ben Gurion airport, Tel Aviv, Israel
    - Hail to the Chief, Nashville style
    - Interview with press secretary Ron Ziegler regarding the possibility of the United States House of Representatives voting for the impeachment of Richard Nixon, undated
    - Midway crash and Watergate by Sherman H. Skolnick
    - Nixon, Richard, remarks to the Veterans of Foreign Wars convention, Sheraton Park Hotel, Washington, D.C., undated
      Includes introduction and speech by Representative George Mahon.
    - Nixon, Richard, remarks to the Young Republican leadership conference, Shoreham Hotel, 1974 February 28
    - Nixon, Richard, remarks at dedication of Grand Ole Opry (2 cassettes), 1974 March 16
    - Photo opportunity with Tricia Nixon Cox and Edward Cox to a crowd in Lafayette park, 1974 January 31
    - Press briefing by Leonard Garment, Fred Buzhardt and Ron Ziegler, undated
- Photographs, 1946-1975; 300 prints, 1 postcard / 31 envelopes (Photo file)
  - 1 postcard and 1 print depicting the view of Rajghat Memorial, New Delhi, India, undated (Envelope A)
  - 26 prints of Gerald Warren relating to his speech before the U.S. Suburban Press Convention in Chicago, Illinois (1975), and his trip to China (1972), and some depicting him with other individuals, including Richard Nixon, 1969-1975 (Envelope B-C)
  - 18 prints of Gerald Warren with other people, including Henry Kissinger, George Shultz and Mrs. Richard Nixon, 1971-1973 (Envelope mD)
  - 7 prints of President and Mrs. Nixon and the family; 2 prints depicting the dresses worn by Mrs. Nixon and Mrs. Howard Cox on the occasion of the marriage of Tricia Nixon and Edward Cox, 1971, 1974 (Envelope E)
  - 6 prints of President Nixon relating to his inauguration and delivery of a radio address; and 2 prints of the presidential seal, 1973-1974 (Envelope F)
  - 26 prints depicting President Nixon with the press, the cabinet wives, and other individuals, including Alexander Haig, Gerald Ford, Alan Greenspan and Henry Kissinger, 1956-1974 (Envelope G-H)
  - 2 prints of Red Square, Moscow, and 19 prints of President Nixon and Mr. Brezhnev with others, undated (Envelope I)
  - 16 prints relating to President Nixon's trip to China and his visit with Mao Tse-tung, 1972 (Envelope J)
    Includes photographs of the Great Wall.
  - 5 prints depicting President Nixon with George Shultz, James Kilpatrick and others, 1971-1974 (Envelope mK)
  - 198 prints depicting President Nixon with leaders of the Middle East, including Anwar Sadat, Golda Meir and Hafex Assad, 1974 (Envelope mL)
    Includes photographs of Mrs. Nixon and Henry Kissinger.
  - 20 prints depicting the Republican Convention, undated (Envelope mM)
    Includes the photographs of Mr. and Mrs. Spiro Agnew, Robert Dole and Ronald Reagan.
  - 1 print of Col. H. C. Manson, personal pilot for General George C. Marshall, photographed with the General on a mission to China; 4 prints of Henry Kissinger with Chou En-lai and others; 1 print of Timothy G. Elbourne, who accompanied President Nixon to China, 1946, 1972 (Envelope N)
  - 14 prints relating to Henry Kissinger's meetings with the Vietnamese leaders and his trip to Vietnam, 1973 (Envelope O)
  - 8 prints of Henry Kissinger and other individuals who represented the United States and the Republic of Vietnam during the Paris peace talks, 1973 (Envelope P)
  - 8 prints depicting Peter Peterson, Michael Balzano, Charles Meyer, John Mitchell, William Rogers, Henry Kissinger and Harold Burroughs, undated (Envelope Q)
  - 6 prints of President Gerald Ford, including 1 with Mrs. Ford, 1974-1975 (Envelope R)
  - 2 prints depicting President Ford with other individuals, including Henry Kissinger, 1974 (Envelope mS)
  - 16 prints of President Ford with others, including Henry Kissinger, Nelson Rockefeller and Scowcroft, 1969-1975 (Envelope T-U)
    Includes 2 prints of President Ford aboard Air Force One.
  - 9 prints depicting Robert McBride; Gustavo Diaz Ordez, President of Mexico and his wife; and Francisco Medina Ascencio, governor of the state of Jalisco, and his wife, undated (Envelope V)
    Includes a photograph of Hotel Camino Real, Puerto Vallarta.
  - 1 print of President and Mrs. Lyndon Johnson and Hubert Humphrey, undated (Envelope W)
  - 4 prints depicting Camp David, 1972 (Envelope X)
  - 6 prints depicting the new Grand Ole Opry House at Opryland and the star Minnie Pearl, 1974 (Envelope Y)
  - 10 prints depicting the Nicaraguan relief mission, 1972 (Envelope Z)
  - 9 prints of President and Mrs. Nixon with other individuals, undated (Envelope AA)
  - 5 prints (miscellaneous), including 1 depicting Wolf Trap Farm Park, and 1 depicting an army helicopter, carrying secret service agents, going down in the Atlantic off the Bahamas, 1973 (Envelope BB)
  - 17 prints depicting President Nixon with other unidentified individuals, undated (Envelope mCC)
  - 6 prints relating to President Nixon's visit to a military base in northern Florida, 1973 (Envelope mDD)
  - 1 print depicting three unidentified individuals in a meeting discussing 1970 budget totals; 1 print depicting Daniel Moynihan with others; and 1 print depicting a large number of people gathered together in a social setting, 1969-1974 (Envelope mEE)
- 1995 Incremental Material, 1970-1994 (Box-folder 228: 46)
  Nixon-related materials, consisting of a memorandum for the President (7 December 1970), paper on "White House Communications Leadership Responsibilities" (25 March 1971), card of voice call signs from the White House Communications Agency (August 1974), a photo of Nixon on his 75th birthday (9 January 1988), a letter from Nixon to Warren (8 March 1988), and a newspaper article on the occasion of Nixon's death (24 April 1994).
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1970-1974 (Box 228)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled, unclassified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2016 February release of declassified records, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 228: 47)
    Telegrams, memoranda, and newspaper clipping, often from the Secretary of State or Department of Defense, relating to military and political situations and U.S. foreign policy in Laos, Vietnam, Chile, and the Middle East.
  - 2018 release of declassified records, 1970-1974 (Reading room workstation)